What is good everyone welcome to today's charting session today is Sunday January 26th, 2025
Tabia going over well this week's price action the trades that we ended up taking
And yeah, let's get into it. So Monday was a bank holiday. So I'm gonna skip over Monday
Let's just get straight into
Tuesday
Which is right here? I am
All right, so coming into Tuesday
Let's just pull up the daily bias and
What I was looking at coming into Tuesday
Tuesday was what the 21st
So we had around a 300 point move during age of session
So I was expecting a lot of choppiness during New York
This was a really really bad week and the common theme of this week was just bad am and then good PM price action
So I was trading a lot of PM session. I think I took
Two days or I traded PM session so we'll go over PM session because that's where I took you know
That's why I made the majority of profits this week
But yeah, so just bad am and there was really good PM session this week
Just doing the work with New York like this is what happens when you see age of session have like a three-in-a-point move
You're gonna expect New York to chop and then PM be good, which is what happened almost every day this week
So yeah, we had this nice SMT. I wasn't really leaning any any way
I'm still bullish and the whole entire week. I was extremely bullish
Being that we were just trending up towards all-time highs. Yes had a lot of that low resistance liquidity that we were looking at
So it was a really obvious draw higher
We just kept having these SMTs but without any structure to validate going lower
So the majority of my daily biases I sent out this week was just still bullish until there's a clear flip in that order flow
Okay, so Tuesday, I don't think I took any trades. Let's just
Check this out though
Yeah, we did take it pretty given
So this is the first trade we took
We ended up going lower at open there was that bearish bias towards London there was that London Judas right
London lows didn't really train to anything significant that sponsor this move so
That was a pretty obvious strong liquidity and then from there you could expect
Along from off that which is what we were looking for right so we got that short at open with no entry
And then after that we ended up getting this really clean form in an IFG
And price action for the most part ended up looking super clean
I ended up getting a fill around here and then I ended up going break even
Once we hit this high here and then we also had an unfilled 15-minute gap
So this was a mech model up to the 15-minute gap right up here
Unfortunately this ended up getting stopped at a break even I think had he ended up taking
some TP
And it did eventually end up hitting this was just super super slow delivery really just choppy delivery
And not good PA whatsoever and a pity I'm like 12 o'clock
So like definitely a horrible price action
Again, this is like a common theme where we'll see really really bad price action during AM and then good price action in PM
So yes, the draw did end up hitting I'm not holding through this though
But yeah, I don't know just being a break even trade overall and I don't think I took any PM trades on Tuesday
So let's just get into the next day if anyone has any questions on this data
It was a good I
Didn't get breakeven nice
I held through it that's crazy
At 157 what happened I 157
I
Was a trade a little long nice I don't think I took this
Did I take this
No
Looks good though nice low-long probably break even our TP one all right
And SMT is a
Is a divergence between assets so I'm Q and ES they move correlated
One there's let's say this low gets taken on NQ and ES doesn't take that low and it's maybe up here
And that's an SMT divergence, but yeah, definitely look at that T trades video. It's a
It's a good video explaining SMTs
Okay, let's go into next day. This is one day again
Just still delivering bullish. We are still just disrespecting these SMTs still trending higher
And there was really no delivery lower which is why I really didn't like any sort of shorts this whole week
Because I was still bullish and there's nothing really for me to tell me otherwise, okay?
So coming into Wednesday again, I think I was bullish again on Wednesday
Yeah, bullish bias today we had this SMT
So what I expected from this SMT is for us to maybe have some sort of
Rebalance of the range maybe some sort of CI ST trade down a London lows then get some delivery off of that the same way
We got it on the day before and on Tuesday where we had that sell off and then we got the long off of one and lows
I kind of want to see that exact thing happen again
because it also was in this kind of
Volume and balance that I wanted to see get traded back to so
That's what I was looking at at open. I wanted to see oh wait. I'm looking at something else right here
Yeah, I just kind of wanted to see that rebalance of the range. It was kind of just awkward positioning of
Where we were
but yeah, I wanted to see an open low high close being that we had all this generated cell sila liquidity, right?
We ended up opening and
Not really having a good
Open low high close being that we just took this out in pre-market and then 930 ended up distributing and
Yeah, the only setup I saw really was this long here
There was this long this was pretty good. We traded into a five-minute
breaker block right here
We also had like just yeah the CISD right this was overall a good long
I did just want to see another manipulation down to this five-minute gap
And I know if I was like industry and I took this long I would have been like super soft stop by this unfold five-minute
Even though we did trade it to three minute. I just want to see another manipulation
Anyways didn't get it
Not this is not like a good setup. I don't think and then this long here was another good setup
But we left equal lows right here. So
Just leaving spread apart equal lows like this is not good. I don't like longing against that
So yeah, I didn't end up taking a long here. We ended up having this inversion for all you got right here
And again, I'm not taking this because we left those equal lows, right?
And that I ended up playing out though
And then here's the short that I wanted to take so this was actually a really good short
I was about to take it. We ended up having just a pretty nice mech model
I think we swept out this biceye liquidity here on ES. So we had like a nice SMT
And then we had some sort of unfilled 15-minute below us and we also had equal lows, right?
So we had these equal lows right here, which was this unfilled 30-minute and we also had these equal lows here
So overall like this was the short setup I was looking at I didn't end up taking this because
It just took way too long like you guys have to understand and remember this is why this is also why just journaling is so important
When you journal you remember not only like the losing trades, which is so important
But you remember the winning trades like you remember how good price action can be and you remember how good delivery can actually be
Right, it's like that three-kandal pattern formation of an inversion of making the gap and then inverting right after like you know what good price action looks like
Right
So when you're just like oh like debating whether this setup is good
It takes like 30 candles to invert it is like most likely not right this took
So long to just invert some one-minute bearish gap. We just left low resistance liquidity like not good delivery
Not good price action whatsoever really really trash am session
And yeah, just overall not not not not anything good
um
And yeah, so that's hot. Does anyone have any questions for this day?
I did not end up taking this short here
But so I don't have any questions
Is it relevant if we make equal lows on an cube and not m and q?
Only relevant on an q. I wouldn't focus on m and q ever just only for entries really
um
There's gonna be a lot of times to
Dude if you're if you're someone who actively trades on m and q
Just make sure you're always looking at the nq chart. There's also been times where like
um
And q will fucking inverse and m and q won't buy like a take and it'll throw you off a lot
And then yeah, only focus on like equal lows and equal highs on nq. So yeah
Yeah, I can try to add some on q and surround you
Yeah, let me check out 1223
1223 you said there was a set up
I don't really trade lunch hour, but let's see
On full 15 minute here
Lot of chop
What was the set up
Oh right here short right here
Not bad. Yeah, not about short
Um
All right, so now I ended up taking two trades in am session there was some
There's there's no best time frame for a c i cd just as long as you're using time frame alignment. That's all that matters um
So right on my mouth bro
Let's type in that john out
so
I ended up taking these two trades in pm session
Um, this was the first trade I ended up taking I ended up taking this long here
So what I was looking at
Really was we had this we were still inside of this hourly for valigat and we're inside of this hourly order block
So what I could have waited for really really is just the test into the opening price of this order block
Um, and maybe that's why I got stopped on this first trade
but
but um
Yeah, overall I like to set up a lot again
We're inside of that hourly for valigat hourly order block
Um, we also had like these equal lows right here and then we swept them and then we just got like a immediate momentum off of this
And then we had triple equal highs and an unfilled five minutes so this was just like textbook textbook setup
um
The only thing I didn't like was again that hourly order block
So I went in a little bit lower risk on this first trade because I did see potential
For it to go lower
Um, I ended up getting stopped out pretty much immediately on this first trade um, and then we hit the hourly order block
Like I expected and then I reentered longs right here at the retest of this or I think just at this close
um
With the stop loss here for a 1-0 1.71RR
so
I ended up taking this long right here and then ended up playing out and this was also turned out to be an unfilled 15 minute
So yeah, just like overall really really good long
Um, how come you took two trades in a day showing you normally just stick to one or is it dependent on what you get on the day
Yeah, good question. So I um trade one to two I take one to two trades sometimes one to four one to three usually like um
I don't limit myself to one traded day
I used to when I was just like kind of unprofitable and still a beginner in the markets
And I always do suggest that for people to stick with one trade a day
Um, and you always hear me telling like beginner traders like do trade like one trade a day is really all you need
Um, because anything after that I feel like a lot of people just get
Super emotional um, there's a bunch of emotions that get built up
Um, when you take more than one trade a day, but since you know, I've been trading for a while now
I don't
Obviously I saw the motions, but it's very different where I'm able to actually manage them
So no, I don't limit myself to just one traded day as long as I see my model and see my setup present itself
I'll take it um, but I do like to take only two trades a day high quality setups
Um, yeah, I I won't my I have a max loss limit of um, 1% so
For when I'm like building and that depends on like where I am overall, but
Yeah, there's days where like price action is pretty slow things aren't like delivery
Powerfully I guess so you'll probably go low risk and you can take two to three trades
Um, but then there's days where it's good volatility price action is moving fucking great
Drama like we used clear everything is playing out and your first trade will be a bang and you can just call it there
So
I just I just typed it out, but I think like one way to see it is like on good days you want to be able to capitalize of course
And then on mid days, you know try to avoid taking too many trades and chasing profits. So
Yeah
Okay
Let's get into ones they know
Um
Wednesday or no, that was just one say it's Thursday
Okay
All right
This is the 23rd
All right, so Thursday I did have again a sh just a bullish bias, but again the trend of the whole entire week was
I just wanted to see that manipulation lower at open and we just kept we're we just weren't
Getting that we just kept like just distributing it open, but again, I was looking to see this AMD
Accumulation, I wanted to see manipulation at open and then distribute to London highs
Um, and it was bullish overall, but I had this kind of short-term bearish bias
Um towards that previous day low and towards less London lows just any area here
Um, I'm looking to see an AMD at open taking out those levels and then distribute higher to those data highs and higher
So that's what I was looking at um
And
When I was
Yeah, so at open that's exactly what I was looking at right we ended up having more accumulation here
And then at open and this had to be I think the worst price action day I've ever seen in my life
um
Not gonna lie like I this was like astonishing like how bad this was just super fucking
choppy there was Trump speaking at 11
um
But yeah, that was pretty much it there there was one setup like one setup here
That was that I actually was going to take and it was this short
Um, but again, we took 30 candles to invert this gap and then we left equal highs right here
Just like really bad setup. So no, this was just
nothing good um
And then we didn't even take out this cell side
And then we just traded higher traded lower trade higher. I mean, there's really nothing to commentate about this
But
What I was looking for then was again, London high so we ended up not manipulating lower and that's fine
Um, but we did end up creating this 15 minute bullish gap
Um, leaving behind a condition right so this is the first gap we left the whole session
And this was a great condition right if we respect it and we get lower time for him structure out of it
Then where should we go London highs like I expected and then if we disrespect it then we could go lower and then maybe get a PM long
So that's what I was really looking at um once Trump started speaking
I there was like a lot of like random candles random volatility happening happening really obviously horrible choppy price action
so I risked
200 or I think $300 on this trade
Um, there was a long setup right here that actually did like a lot um and I'm getting stopped out of this for $300
um, and this was again that same that really it was a really nice setup to London highs and previous day high
ended up hitting but I'll show you what it was is that
We ended up trading here one minute CISD we got an inversion for value app right here
And I wanted to see London highs and higher
I had a stop loss just at this breaker block right here
so
Yeah, I just ended up getting stopped out. I didn't want to put it all the way down at the wick. It just
That's just like it was just way too big of a stop the breaker block if your bullish should hold
But since we were so choppy and since the delivery was so bad and I've getting stopped out
I think I might have
No, I think yeah, I just got stopped out
And then from there price did end up running and we did end up going all the way to the higher targets
But let's just go into the second trade I took the day on the day
And it was again in PM session because of how much cleaner
Just look how much better this price action is just like so much better than there's this choppy shit
But uh first off before I move on just I don't have any questions on the this lost Isaac
Okay, looks like we're good um, so let's just get into PM then because I didn't I did end up taking a trade in PM session
um, we ended up having a really nice SMT at this high at the internal highs
Then we also had an SMT with the external highs right here to an SMT with this high and then also these highs here
So it was really nice. There was a previous day high SMT as well as internal high SMT
And it was just a very simple mech model. We had an unfilled 50 minute gap right here. I posted this trade
um
And it was a four minute iFG
So we had a four minute iFG here. I waited for retest
Um, and then I ended up getting filled right there. I didn't hold all the way down here
I ended up just closing there because it was a one to two rr
And I just needed that amount of profit to secure payout. I think I closed more around here something
Um, but yeah, this was just the trade I took
Zero drawdown. I top ticked this shit. It was beautiful
Um, I'm going to the crazy shit I'm gonna see in my life. Yeah, so this was that I don't think I've ever actually seen that like
Literally not even a singular tick. Yeah, I showed that show is beautiful
But yeah, I was just off of the four minute
Um
Um, and am such an price end up going to Asia highs, but in terms of
Getting all confluence is satisfied. You think Asia highs left is fine or no?
Um
I don't really understand your question what do you mean
In terms of getting all confluence is satisfied
What do you mean
You guys beginner when you get these conditions choppy and am
Um, do you suggest staying only to am and not taking traders at a kid to try to PM?
um
Yeah, I'm just what David probably did so back dust
Persevere
But um, yeah, usually if again if am's choppy PM will be clean
But the whip is stop loss like a rule
I don't know
Oh my god
What's the squirk to the game?
Fuck
Um
Like London high-hat you have your confluence is iFG etc
Would you wait for Asian highs to get here? Just so for the short since we already took all of that by side
I don't know what maybe you're looking like Asia highs. I don't care about any buy start level like here because we took it all
I think that's some tea was all the way here
There was a huge SMT with the previous day high
So there was no need for price to go higher here when we had this unfilled 15 minute gap right here, right?
So
On that tree took intermediate low. Yeah, but I don't care since we didn't take the draw the draw on the quid
It was still this and also lower could I have held till here sure um
But one to two hours on you to make red
Um when looking for retests like this trade we need to see first like the intermediate
Um at all, I mean it's really just screen time, but like
Like there's times where I'll go break even if the enemy it lowers take it and there's times where I won't
There's times where you know not take the trade if the enemy it lowers take and there's times where I will
um
Like as long as the the draw is not taken like for example here like what I was mainly looking
I was the 15 minute gap. I don't really care about anything else as long as 15 minute gap is not traded to then it's still valid for a mech model
um
so yeah
Why didn't you hold the equal lows because I just needed this amount of money to get a payout so
um
And it was a one to two are I didn't need anything more than that
Um on that short I targeted the accumulation lows
Again, yeah, it's taking some sort of wick liquidity always a requirement for your model
Key levels also work. Yeah, I just I just use key levels
um
What stopped you from over trading um
I mean there's not really like one like again there there wasn't like one thing that stopped me from over trading
I guess it was just
A lot of like years of just that should happening where I would keep trying it and it wouldn't work and then just got to a point where it's like
You know that the market
The money you make when you over trade is not yours. It's gonna get you're gonna give it right back to the markets eventually
um
No matter like oh my god
Well, I made money and I made the money back on this day
So I should try to get the next day. It's like that mindset and that mentality is never gonna work
So just knowing that you know the that money's not yours and to stop treating it like it is
So
Yeah, I mean, I'm just just
It was just years of fucking I was a year of straight up not following my rules. I got sick and tired of it
Um
Buddy just skip it's cuz I just answered that question
Do you think 2023 had shitty p.a. In compared to 2024
Because I'm back to you in 2023 and I found it very abstract
Um
No, I don't I don't think so I think 20 anything was really good
I've I've backed us to the majority of 2023 and the recording stop so you can check it out there
Um
Okay, let's go into the next and final day
Which was right right here
All right, so Friday this was actually this was the best pa we got all week
Um
Yeah, this was the best pa we've gone all week which was this there was really good setups actually
So first being this short we had a really beautiful short um an am session or we had a bunch of generation of lr
l
Um, we had these equal highs here and we also had a really really clean SMT with previous a high so
At open we ended up trading higher and it up taking out those highs and
up forming that bearish SMT
And then we ended up getting a few trades so there was this one minute short here. It wasn't my favorite um
The one that I did really like though and this was also because there was 10 am news
um
The short of the day had to have been
Right here. So this was definitely like the best play all week to be honest
This five minute ifg. I did not end up taking this for a lot of reasons
Number one is I was just overall still bullish yes was extremely close to just all not extremely close all time highs
But it was like right up here and yes had like a bunch of lr right here
Um, so I was just overall bullish
I did of course want to see this play happen to then take a long
Which is what I've been you know waiting for the whole entire time
But I just wasn't that confident that we had a five minute ifg and then we also still held this volume imbalance right here
So definitely it was a little bit sus we are also inside of a 15 minute gap right here
um
We also had data highs right here
Just a lot of influences for me to not take the trade
But in hindsight could I have taken it just based on draw on liquidity? Yes um and regarding everything else yes
Because it was in place for a really really nice sell and a really good short and overall it was a really good play
So this was definitely a really good short to take
Um, but then the play right after um
Damn, who is the guy that said this short snuck this long after is not gonna work when we were waiting for our long
I we took the screenshot. Yeah, I need to find it. I need to find it
That bro was on
His fucking bro. He was like super convinced. I was not gonna play out. I just being shot at that shit too. I had it on my screen
It wasn't Eric
I was an Eric it wasn't Eric
You find it really quick
I can't find it
Main screenshots and act just like disappear, bro
Damn
Yeah, there it is
Father David
Look at this fucker. Longs aren't gonna play out. Oh, and he's in chat. Bro was mad quiet. Wow
Yeah, and I buddy signal bought the dealer too
Anyways
Um, okay, so there was a few setups we were looking at
Um, this was the first long that I was gonna take
This was the long right here. We had a woman at ifg
Um
Yeah, there was a lot of stuff here, okay, first was like one minute, but there was a three minute
So I was waiting for the three minutes to get inverted
Um, and I'm getting inverted and then the clothes was just yeah, that's that's just a high estrogen
entry right there a high testosterone requires one minute
I saw the one minute didn't care to check all their time frames. All right. Wow. Was that on purpose?
Yeah, for sure buddy. Yeah, I purposely took the one minute and definitely
knew that there's a four minute no, it doesn't matter
But then there was that retracement into rebounds which um
I went in on all my accounts, but one account I scaled in
Actually, one account. I only went in at that rebounds right there, which was fucking beautiful
Um, and that was a good one. It's like Blake said last time when when was it bro? We took a trade and you were saying that
You didn't like that we just
Sort of aggressively ran through
The inversion and we most likely retraced blah blah blah and you don't want to go break even now awesome motion
But yeah, when you have those leg ups like that
uh, like for example that inversion with just a lot of upcoding candles and you have that really bullish leg
Uh, chances are you'll probably get a rebounds and you can get like some equal every um entry
So down was nice and then Blake took the inversion right after that which is solid is
You broke your rules and not trading 11. Okay
That's just
All right, he's he's rage baby. I know he's rage baby. He's rage okay. I'm a I'm a guy
I need to watch this fucking bills again
Okay, then after that um, I took a two-minute long
Taking this two minutes to unfilled 15 to the unfilled gap
This was based off of we traded back into this three-minute ifg
We ended up getting a
bounce off of that two-minute was right here the close on this also ended up being pretty horrendous
So I waited for a retrace got my retrace
Um, then I ended up being under the demon. I think I closed I did close a little bit earlier because there was an SMT
Ended up playing out for about that one to one or rather
So really nice trade in am session um
I'm sorry like just on friday. This was just the best price action we got all week
Which is pretty funny being how shit and slow the delivery was but to be honest like
This was the best price action we got in all week the most amount of setups I've seen um and that's that
Does anyone have any questions on this trigger here?
But it was butter
All right, let me get into the shibby all right, why'd you take it past 11 anytime a.m. Generates liquidity and doesn't need draw
11 a.m. will typically go ahead and run it. Uh, it's as simple as that
It's not just like we don't just trade 11 for fun to trade 11 um no
a.m. lack of delivery 11 a.m. will typically cook
So just a little thing to be
Iying out if you ever see you know a.m. Doesn't really deliver to draw
You can stay on for another 20 30 minutes and see if something presents off starting 11 a.m. simple as that
um
Cool cool. Yeah, I'm not required